Note to recruiting manager: If you did obtain this résumé from me via a Microsoft Github link, it may be outdated. Please save or view the most recent version, hosted on Github.

Honoured with the Good Citizenship award by my high school peers and staff, I take great pride in the respect I have for people – I appreciate all opportunities to engage with others and improve their lives. To acquire a diverse world view, I follow articles, books and podcasts on data management, psychology and entrepreneurship. My passion for people, experiences, and ambitions have influenced my professional interests – to create operational, strategic and risk management frameworks for scalable ventures as I become a professional in data science and the industries that it supports.

### **Education**

2021-09 – 2022-09

## Master of Real Estate Finance – in progress

Henley Business School, Reading, England

- Coursework on economics, securities, futures, options, fixed income & equity, funding, development processes & appraisals, valuation, and global markets & investment. All in the context of real estate
- Dissertation proposal on retail property

2019-02 – 2021-03

## Master of Computer Science by Dissertation: Data Science – with distinction

University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg, South Africa

 Dissertation on multivariate time series analysis, anomaly detection, natural language processing, metric design and forecasting

2018-02 – 2018-12

## Bachelor of Science Honours: Big Data Analytics

University of the Witwatersrand

- Research report on algorithms for fraud detection
- Coursework in Statistics, Computer Vision, General Machine Learning, Optimisation, Data Analysis, Visualisation and Image Processing

2015-02 – 2017-12

# Bachelor of Science: Economics and Mathematics

University of the Witwatersrand

 Coursework in Mathematics, Computer Science, Information Systems, Economics and Accounting,

# **Bill Seota**

## **Personal Information**

**Phone** 

+27 84 381 7712

E-mail

bseota@gmail.com

LinkedIn

Bill Seota

# Skills and Technical Applications

Please click the link below for the price optimisation dashboard:

**Price Optimisation** 

Please click the link below for the company metrics dashboard:

**EverSparc** Dashboard

Please click the link below for my Github page:

**Github** 

Public Speaking and Presentations

Python for data modelling, forecasting and visualisation

Python for Computer Vision

SQL

Python for Recommender Systems

Git

## **Work History**

#### **Data and Investment Analyst** 2020-11 -

2021-06 Bopa Moruo Private Equity Fund Managers, Johannesburg

> Prepared financial reporting and operational dashboards for investor due-diligence and portfolio company reports. The above description entailed the following activities:

- 1. Streamlining the financial reporting and visual analysis workflows – data modelling and presentation of analyses
- 2. Modelling operational efficiency within its portfolio companies by leveraging data from Bopa Moruo and its investees
- 3. Providing investment appraisals to the investment team
- 4. Automating 1 and 2 to improve the efficiency of 3

#### 2020-09 -**Customer Pricing Analyst** 2020-11

Tiger Consumer Brands Limited, Johannesburg

- Worked with the data scientist to prepare product category sales data
- Uploaded and maintained the profitability dashboard for the spreads, vegetables, condiments, and desserts product categories

#### **Product Developer** 2020-06

Moya, Johannesburg

Moya's BlackBook was a fintech product to help small retail and service businesses obtain loans using transactions and macroeconomic data. As one of Moya's three founders, I was responsible for:

- 1. BlackBook's conception and its early phase production
- 2. Building Moya's integrated three-statement models, debt schedules, cash flow and sensitivity analyses
- 3. Developing relationships with merchants and consulting loan providers

#### 2019-10 -AlphaCode Explore Incubate Member 2020-06

AlphaCode & Explore Data Science Academy, Johannesburg I worked on business formulation and strategies around the BlackBook fintech product, covering the following tasks:

- 1. Using data science to scale organisations
- 2. Business thinking for 10x ventures
- 3. Design thinking and design sprints
- 4. Prototyping and testing BlackBook with our clients

# 2019-08 -

#### 

J. P. MORGAN Corporate and Investment Bank, Johannesburg

- Trained by my line manager to understand the technology design and usage that ensures optimum transaction flow into, within and out of the Bank
- Consulted with the 12 other line managers (Corporate and Investment Banking, Equity Research, Finance, Treasury, Trading, Sales, Operations, Compliance, Technology Infrastructure, Client Onboarding, Business Management) on their integrations within the Bank, and completed three projects involving the Finance, Operations and Technology departments

## 2019-09 – Entrepreneur-In-Training

2019-12

Investec Startup School, Cape Town, South Africa

- Worked alongside mentors to expand my understanding of business models as well as internal and external drivers of an organisation
- Developed two business plans for my operationalinnovation ideas for small enterprises

## 2016-05 – Counsellor and Council Member 2018-12 Mathematical Science Student Council

Mathematical Science Student Council, University of the Witwatersrand

- I was tasked with helping students who needed academic planning and guidance
- As a council, we ensured the well-being of Science students regarding fair satisfactory performance criteria
- In 2016, I was of seven students from a voluntary committee that introduced supplementary lessons and supplementary examinations for second-year Mathematics modules – the pass rate improved by 70%

## **Certificates and Courses**

2020-07	Yale University – Financial Markets
2020-07	Duke University – Startup Company Valuation Methods
2020-06	Udemy – Mergers & Acquisitions and Disinvestment
2020-04	Udemy – Company Valuation: Integrated Statements & Forecasting
2020-03	Udemy – Complete CFA Modules (Course)
2019-09	SAIIA EU-SA Youth for Climate Action Conference – Volunteering
2019-09	IBM Data Science Acceleration Course
2019-05	Huawei 5G Overview Training Course
2014-11	Good Citizenship Award – Cornwall Hill College (CHC)
2014-10	Public Speaking: Toastmasters, Senior Best Speaker – CHC

## **Leadership Roles**

2019-05 – Present	Volunteering – Member of Young Global Entrepreneurs
2019-11	IBM Quantum Computing Summer School
2017-10 – 2018-10	ABSIP Investment Society: Promoting membership – Wits
2014-01 – 2014-11	First Aid: Captain – CHC
2014-01 – 2014-11	Chess Captain: First team – CHC
2014-01 – 2014-11	Student Representative: Head of House – CHC
2013-06 – 2013-11	Football Captain: Centurion Blues Football Club

## **Hobbies and Interest Groups**

Short-distance track events

Venture and growth capital origination

Quantitative Finance

Stocks, Trading

RAIL Labs (Robotics, Autonomous Intelligence and Learning) Group

Toastmasters

## **References**

Samuel Kamara – Vice President, Finance, SoftBank Investment Advisers

Lucky Kgosiemang, Technology Associate, J.P. Morgan

Prof Samuel Azasu – Associate Professor, Wits

Dr Bukirwa Irene Kamara – Founder, Young Global Entrepreneurs

Ntsika Ntsokolo – Equity Analyst, PSG Wealth

Nox Mlalazi – Deal Executive, Athena Capital

André Ross – Executive Director, J.P. Morgan

Preashnie Padayachee – Executive Director, J. P. Morgan

Lesiba Mothata – Head of Strategic Clients, Alexander Forbes

Nimisha Naik - Lecturer, Economics, Wits

Dr David van der Walt – Managing Director, Vizier Advisors